# Chhaganlal B S

# Project and Implementation Lead

I am a motivated and analytical project lead with more than 2 years & 10 months of experience in global payroll services, specialized in project implementation. In my current role, I have been responsible for rolling out a new automation program that has helped more people in my team to achieve the larger payroll implementation project in a short span of time. I am proud of my solid track record of delivering projects that have had proven business benefits and am now looking to take on greater responsibility.

chaganlal17@gmail.com

PLOT NO 10 180/181 NAVARATHINAPURAM 3RD STREET, KAMARAJAR SALAI, Madurai, India

in linkedin.com/in/chhaganlal-b-s-425405107

S live:chhaganlal.sundararajan

+91-962-919-9050

chhaganlal17.github.io/po/

₩ @chaganlal17

github.com/Chhaganlal17

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Team Lead

### Neeyamo Enterprise Solutions Pvt Ltd

12/2020 - Present

Tacke

- As TL, I'm handling a team of 10 specialists both in global payroll implementation and operations. Primarily Handling countries like EMEA (Morocco, Kenya, Nigeria, South Africa, Egypt, and Tunisia) and in AMER Region (Chile, Peru, and Panama)
- Have Implemented both integration (Workday) and nonintegration projects for 15+countries
- Well versed in payroll training. So far, I have trained around 200+ employees in Payroll, Implementation, and Configuration process
- Knowledge on HRIS integration via workday
- Handling 6 countries with 3000+payslips monthly on a weekly, monthly, semi-monthly, and bi-weekly basis
- Performing audit activities using SOC 1 Methodology as per the regulations to make sure that the standard process is followed without any deviation
- Handling shadow payroll scenarios by analyzing the COC
- Raised Kaizen for Automation project to implement and Using Kanban methodology to track the process
- Coaching and mentoring associates based on their skill-set identification, situation handling
- Managing Career Path planning for all team members

### Associate Team Lead

#### Neeyamo Enterprise Solutions Pvt Ltd

06/2018 - 11/2020

Tasks

- Act as a lead, to assign the work and driving the team to achieve the 100% accuracy rate within the SLA
- Collecting, calculating, and entering data in order to maintain and update payroll information
- Compiling summaries of earning, taxes, deduction, leave, and non-taxable wages and reporting on this
- Establish strong client relationships and deliver sustained stable payroll operations
- Responding to employee queries quickly by identifying and resolving their issues
- Took part in BCMS plan during pandemic to ensure payroll functionality without disruption

# **SKILLS**



# **PROJECTS**

#### Payroll Implementation

 Have Implemented payroll for countries like Nigeria, Morocco, Tunisia, Germany, Australia and New Zealand, etc.

#### Payroll Inhouse Project

 Payroll process for Countries namely Tunisia, Morocco and Cameroon has been processed in-house for various clients

#### **Automation Project**

 Using Selenium Automation, have automated the configuration process for various modules

#### System Setup

 Country logics have been well analyzed and those logics have been accommodated in the Neeyamo's payroll system for multiple countries

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Extra Mile award for best outstanding performance (08/2018 - 09/2018)

And in May 2020, awarded extra mile again

Wow award for going above and beyond call of duty in (04/2019 - 06/2019)

Torch Bearer Award for Project implementation (11/2020)

Nominated for the employee of the year award 2021

Have completed advanced excel courses in Udemy

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Engineering (EEE)

Sethu Institute of Technology

08/2014 - 05/2018 7.7

HSC

SPVM Higher Secondary School

06/2013 - 04/2014 79.9%

SSLC

SPVM Higher Secondary School

06/2011 - 04/2012 85.2%

**LANGUAGES** 

English Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency

Tamil

Native or Bilingual Proficiency